It’s a great pleasure that from all over the world
Это огромная радость, что здесь собрались люди со всего мира,
people have gathered to worship Shiva.
чтобы поклониться Шри Шиве.
Actually we should say it is Sadashiva that we are going to worship today.
На самом деле, надо сказать, что сегодня мы будем поклоняться Шри Садашиве.
As you know the difference between Sadashiva and Shri Shiva.
Как вы знаете, разница между Шри Садашивой и Шри Шивой заключается в том, что
Sadashiva is the God Almighty
Шри Садашива — Всемогущий Бог,
and He is a witness of the play of the Primordial Mother.
и Он — свидетель игры Первозданной Матери.
The combination between Sadashiva and the Primordial Mother Adi Shakti
Союз Садашивы и Первозданной Матери, Ади Шакти
is just like a moon and the moonlight or the sun or the sunlight.
подобен Луне и лунному свету, или Солнцу и солнечному свету.
We cannot understand such relationship in human being, among human marriages
Мы не можем понять такие отношения на человеческом уровне,
or among human relationships.
или в человеческих отношениях.
So whatever the Adi Shakti’s creating,
Итак, каким бы ни было творение Ади Шакти,
which is the desire of Sadashiva, is being witnessed by Him.
оно желанно Шри Садашивой, и оно находится под Его наблюдением.
And when He is watching this creation
И, наблюдая за этим творением,
He is witnessing all of it into all details.
Он видит буквально всё [творение] во всех деталях.
He witnesses the whole universe
Он наблюдает всю Вселенную,
and He also witnesses this Mother Earth,
а также Он наблюдает за этой Мать-Землей,
all the creation that is done by the Adi Shakti.
всё творение, созданное Шри Ади Шакти.
His power is of witnessing
Его сила — сила свидетеля,
and the power of Adi Shakti
а сила Ади Шакти
is this all pervading power of love.
— это всепроникающая энергия Любви.
So the God Almighty, the Father, the Primordial Father, we can say,
Итак, Бог Всемогущий, Отец, Первозданный Отец, можно сказать,
expresses His desire, His Iccha Shakti as the Primordial Mother
выражает Своё желание, Свою Иччха Шакти в виде Первозданной Матери,
and She expresses Her power as love.
а Она выражает Свою силу в виде Любви.
So the relationship between the two is extremely
Таким образом, отношения между ними очень
understanding, very deep,
понимающие, очень глубокие.
and whatever She‘s creating,
И что бы Она ни создавала,
if She finds, if He finds there is some problem
если Он обнаруживает, что есть какая-то проблема
or there are people, human beings specially
или есть люди, особенно человеческие существа,
who are trying to obstruct Her work, or even the Gods
которые пытаются помешать Её работе, или даже Боги,
who are not the deities are trying to express their egos,
которые не являются божествами, пытаясь проявлять своё эго,
He is the one who brings forth their destruction.
Он тот, кто осуществляет их разрушение.
So He is the one who is responsible for the destructive power.
То есть, Он — тот, кто несёт ответственность за разрушительную силу.
He is reflected in the hearts of human beings,
Он отражён в сердцах людей,
among all the creations He pulsates.
во всех творениях Он пульсирует.
But that pulses, pulsation is the energy of the Primordial Mother.
Но эта пульсация — это энергия Первозданной Матери.
And He can destroy anything that goes against the plans of the Adi Shakti.
И Он может уничтожить всё, что противоречит планам Шри Ади Шакти.
Adi Shakti is love, She forgives and She loves.
Шри Ади Шакти есть любовь, Она прощает и Она любит.
She loves Her creation. She wants the creation to prosper,
Она любит Своё творение. Она хочет, чтобы творение процветало,
to go up to the same level for which it was created.
поднималось до того уровня, ради которого оно было создано.
She wants human beings to go to that level where
Она хочет, чтобы люди достигли того уровня, где
they enter into the Kingdom of God, Kingdom of Sadashiva
они смогут войти в Царство Бога, Царство Шри Садашивы,
where there is bliss, there is forgiveness, there’s joy.
где есть блаженство, прощение, радость.
All this is only possible if you have seeking,
Всё это возможно только в том случае, если вы ищете,
that you have also a innate desire to be there.
если у вас также есть врождённое желание быть там.
This desire within us is reflected as the reflection of the Primordial Mother.
Это желание внутри нас проявляется как отражение Первозданной Матери.